基本构建块之一
One of the fundamental building blocks
互联网是超链接
of the internet are hyperlinks
或者简而言之，只是链接。
or for short, just links.
所以链接才是真正使互联网成为可能的东西
So links are what actually enables the internet
成为一个全球网络。
to be a worldwide web.
所以没有页面之间的链接，
So without links between pages,
不会有网络。
there would be no web.
现在让我们学习
And so let's now learn
如何在我们自己的网页上放置链接。
how to place links on our own webpages.
现在，我们可以将链接分为两大类。
Now, we can place links into two big categories.
第一类是链接
The first category is links
指向我们自己网站内的其他页面。
that point to other pages within our own website.
所以让我们说，在我们的网站上，
So let's say that here in our website,
代码杂志，
The Code Magazine,
我们有另一篇博文。
we had another blog post.
所以我们可以从这个页面创建一个链接
So we could then create a link from this page
到另一页，对吧？
to that other page, right?
现在，另一方面，另一个类别
Now, on the other hand, the other category
是指向我们网站之外的链接。
is links that point to outside of our website.
例如，如果我在这里放置了指向 udemy.com 的链接
So for example, if I placed a link to udemy.com here
在这个页面上，然后那个，当然，
on this page, then that, of course,
将是与外部的链接
would be a link to the outside
我们的网站，对吧？
of our website, right?
现在，我们确实创建了这两种类型的链接
Now, we do create these two types of links
在 HTML 中以完全相同的方式
in the exact same way in HTML
但仍有一些特殊性
but there's still some kinds of particularities
我们需要注意的
that we need to be aware of
所以现在让我们从第二种开始
and so let's now actually start with the second kind
我正在描述的链接，
of link that I was describing,
指向我们自己网站的外部。
which point outwards of our own website.
所以我在演示中所拥有的
So what I have here in the demo
是在这部分的结尾，
is that here at the end of this part,
所以这是什么是HTML部分，
so of this what is HTML section,
我有一个指向 MDN Web Docs 的链接。
I have a link to the MDN Web Docs.
所以这基本上是一个网站
So this is basically a website
在这里您可以了解有关 HTML 的所有信息
where you can learn all about HTML
还有 CSS 和 JavaScript。
and also CSS and JavaScript.
实际上，我会更好地向您展示这个网站
And actually, I will show you this site a little bit better
在下一节
in the next section
因为它对 Web 开发人员很重要
because it's important as a web developer
知道如何使用
to know how to use
并在此 Web 文档页面中查找信息。
and find information here in this web documentations page.
所以我们想要的是抓住那个链接
So what we want is to grab the link of that
所以要做到这一点，
and so to do that,
只是谷歌 MDN，它代表 Mozilla 开发者网络
just google MDN, which stands for Mozilla Developer Network
然后只是 HTML。
and then just HTML.
以及我们将在此处使用的确切 URL
And the exact URL that we're gonna use here
没关系。
doesn't really matter.
我们想要的只是有一些 URL
All we want is to have some URL
这指向我们自己的页面之外。
that points outside of our own page.
对？
Right?
所以让我们在这里抓住这个，
So let's just grab this one here,
这是谷歌的第一个结果。
which was the first Google result.
所以我一次又一次地复制它，
So I'm copying it and again,
请记住，这称为 URL。
keep in mind that this is called a URL.
所以如你所知，
So as you know,
互联网上的每一个网站
every single website on the internet
有自己的网址
has its own URL
这就是我们需要的
and so that is what we need in order
创建指向该页面的链接。
to create a link to that page.
好的？
Okay?
那么让我们看看。
So let's see.
是的，我们想把它放在这里
Yeah, we want to put that right here
在这个无序列表之后。
after this unordered list.
对？
Right?
让我们在演示中看看。
Let's see in the demo.
是的，所以就在有序列表之后。
Yeah, so right here after the ordered list.
所以就在这里。
So that's here.
所以要在 HTML 中创建一个链接，
So to create a link in HTML,
我们使用 a 元素，它代表锚点。
we use the a element, which stands for anchor.
所以从技术上讲，一个超链接
So technically, a hyperlink
或者链接实际上在 HTML 中称为锚点。
or a link is actually called anchor in HTML.
所以它是一个锚元素。
So it is an anchor element.
我们可以关闭它。
We can close it.
那么我们可以这样指定我的内容
Then we can specify some content
然后我们可以，或者我们必须实际关闭它。
and then we can, or we have to actually close it.
所以让我们从这样做开始。
So let's start by doing that.
现在，关于链接的内容，
Now, as for the content of the link,
我们在这里指定的实际上是文本
what we specify here is actually the text
我们希望在页面上显示。
that we want to be displayed on the page.
所以链接的文本。
So the text of the link.
所以在这种情况下，就是这个 MDN Web Docs。
So in this case, that is this MDN Web Docs.
好的？
All right?
所以 MDN 网络文档。
So MDN Web Docs.
但是现在，URL 呢？
But now, what about the URL
我们希望这个链接指向哪里？
where we want this link to point to?
好吧，为此，我们需要再次使用一个属性。
Well, for that, we need to once again use an attribute.
所以在这种情况下，它是 href 属性。
So in this case, it is the href attribute.
然后相等，双引号
Then equal, double quotes
然后我们可以简单地粘贴该 URL
and then we can simply paste that URL
我们在这里复制的
that we copied right here
实际上就是这样。
and that's actually it.
所以如果我现在救它，
So if I give it a save now,
然后在这里重新加载我们的页面，
and then reload our page here,
那么这里是我们的链接。
then here is our link.
你在下面看到，
And you see down there,
所以在这个角落
so here in this corner
当我悬停它时，它实际上向我显示了 URL
that when I hover it, it actually shows me the URL
然后当我点击它时，
and then when I click it,
我们的页面在那里。
our page goes there.
太好了，所以这实际上已经是基础
Great, and so that is actually already the basics
创建一个链接。
of creating a link.
很简单，对吧？
Very simple, right?
现在，我们想要这个链接
Now, we want this link here
实际上就像在这个文本中一样。
to actually be like inside of this text.
因此，在此处的另一段中。
So inside of one more paragraph here.
对？
Right?
所以让我们创建那个段落。
So let's create that paragraph.
因此，您可以在以下位置了解更多信息，
So you can learn more at,
然后这个链接在这里
and then this link here
基本上只是这里文字的延续。
is basically just a continuation of the text in here.
所以在这一段里面。
So inside of this paragraph.
所以我们可以在这里完成我们的句子
So we can finish our sentence here
然后像往常一样关闭我们的段落。
and then close up our paragraph as usual.
所以现在看起来就像原来的一样。
And so now that looks just like in the original one.
对？
Right?
现在，再次注意这里发生的事情
Now, notice what happens here once again
当我点击它时。
when I click it.
所以你看到我们直接导航
So you see that we navigated directly
到这个页面，现在我们自己的页面消失了。
to this page and now our own page disappeared.
所以当然，我们可以回到这里
So of course, we can go back here
但有时我们想做的事
but sometimes what we want to do
是在新选项卡中打开链接。
is to open a link in a new tab.
因此，让我也向您展示我们如何做到这一点。
So let me also show you how we can do that.
当然，我们并不总是想要这样。
And of course, we don't always want that.
很多时候，我们实际上想要页面
So many times, we actually want the page
真正移动到我们在此处指定的 URL
to really move to the URL that we specified here
但有时它也很有用
but also sometimes it's useful
保持页面打开，只需打开 URL
to keep the page open and simply open the URL
在一个新标签中，我们可以做到这一点
in a new tab, and we can do that
通过指定目标属性，
by specifying the target attribute,
然后像往常一样引用
then the quotes as always
然后这个看起来有点奇怪
and then this one looks a bit weird,
所以它是下划线，然后是空白。
so it's underscore and then blank.
所以给它一个保存
So give that a save
当我们重新加载时，它看起来会一样
and when we reload, it will look the same
但行为应该已经改变。
but the behavior should have changed.
确实，请注意它是如何打开一个新标签的
And indeed, notice how it opened a new tab
而我们原来的那个仍然是开放的。
and our original one is still open.
伟大的。
Great.
所以这有效，所以我们现在有一个链接
So that worked and so we have now a link
指向外部的 URL
that points to a URL that is outside
我们自己的网站。
of our own website.
但现在关于第一个场景
But now about that first scenario
我们基本上想链接到一个内部页面。
where we want to link to an internal page basically.
现在让我们这样做。
Let's do that now.
再回到我们的演示，
And going back again to our demo,
我们这里有这个例子。
we have here this example.
小号o 一开始，就在主标题之后，
So in the very beginning, right after the main heading,
我们在这里有这些链接
we have these links here
所以这些应该是链接
and so these are supposed to be links
指向属于此博客的页面。
that point to pages that are part of this blog.
所以现在让我们在这里创建第一个链接，
So let's now create this first link here,
所以博客，并创建一个新页面
so blog, and also create a new page
我们实际上可以链接到的地方。
where we can actually link to.
好的？
Okay?
所以创建一个新页面就这么简单
And so creating a new page is as simple
就像创建一个新的 HTML 文档一样。
as creating a new HTML document.
所以让我们再次打开侧边栏
So let's open up again our sidebar
通过点击这里然后我们基本上在这里看到我们的资源管理器
by clicking here and then we see our explorer here basically
与所有文件
with all the files
然后再一次，我们在这里在这个图标中创建一个新文件
and then again, we create a new file in this icon here
这次我们称之为 blog.html。
and let's call it blog.html this time.
现在我们可以在这里使用这个作弊
And now we could use this cheat here
创建 HTML 结构
to create the HTML structure
但实际上，让我们再在这里练习一下。
but actually, let's practice a little bit here again.
如果你愿意，你甚至可以暂停视频
And if you want, you can even pause the video
并自己输入
and type it out on your own
但我现在会很快在这里完成。
but I will just do it here very fast now.
所以html。
So html.
然后我们当然需要关闭它。
Then we need to close it, of course.
现在，在 html 内部，
Now, inside of the html,
记住，我们有头。
remember, we have the head.
在头部内部，我们通常有一个标题。
Inside of the head, we have a title usually.
而这个，我们就这样称呼它吧，博客。
And this one, let's just call it like this, BLOG.
所以只是大写使它非常明显
So just uppercase to make it really obvious
你看这真的是
and you see that this is really
只是一个非常简单的骨架结构，
just a very bare bones structure,
只是一个有标题的头。
just a head with a title.
事实上，身体也是如此，
And actually, the same for the body,
记住是那个部分
which remember is the part
这将在浏览器中可见。
that is going to be visible in the browser.
所以在这里我将简单地指定一个 h2 元素
So here I will simply specify an h2 element
并在这里关闭它
and close it also here
我们也将其称为 BLOG。
and let's call this one BLOG as well.
好吧，啊，当然，我们还是需要关闭身体。
Okay, ah, we still need to close the body, of course.
就是这样。
And that's it.
让我们拯救它。
Let's give it a save.
所以这里我们有一个非常简单的，
And so here we have a very simple,
非常简单的博客 HTML 文档。
very bare bones blog HTML document.
但现在有了它，
But now with that in place,
我们可以在这里创建超链接或链接
we can create a hyperlink or a link right here
在这个 index.html 中，它将指向那个 blog.html。
in this index.html, which will point to that blog.html.
因此浏览器将导航到该页面。
And so the browser will then navigate to that page.
因此，让我们在 h1 之后立即执行此操作。
So let's do it right here after the h1.
所以锚元素。
And so the anchor element.
然后我们需要href
Then we need the href
所以现在我们在这里做什么
and so now what we do here instead
指定 URL
of specifying a URL
是指定HTML文件的名称
is to specify the name of the HTML file
我们想去的
that we want to go to
所以在这种情况下，当然，
and so in this case, it is, of course,
我们刚刚创建的这个 blog.html。
this blog.html that we just created.
那么这里作为元素的内容，
Then here as the content of the element,
让我们再写一次博客吧
let's just write blog again
然后像往常一样关闭它。
and then close it as always.
给它一个保存。
Give it a save.
这是我们美丽的链接
Here is our beautiful link
现在看看我点击它时会发生什么。
and now watch what happens as I click it.
Bam，我们现在在博客
Bam, we are now at blog
您也可以在 URL 栏中看到。
and you can see that also here in the URL bar.
所以这就是现在所有的这个文件。
So which is now all of this file.
所以所有这条路
And so all of this path
最后是 blog.html。
and then at the end, blog.html.
对？
Right?
现在，要返回，我们当然可以点击这里
Now, to go back, we could, of course, click here
在这个后退按钮上，但我们还可以做什么
on this back button but what we could also do
就是在这里加个链接，
is to add a link here,
它只是指向 index.html。
which simply points back to index.html.
对？
Right?
这听起来是个好主意，不是吗？
That sounds like a nice idea, doesn't it?
所以让我们回到 blog.html
So let's come back here to blog.html
作为另一个挑战，
and as yet another challenge,
现在我希望您自己实际创建此链接。
now I want you to actually create this link on your own.
所以在这里暂停视频并创建一个链接
So pause the video here and create a link
指向 index.html。
that points back to index.html.
那你做到了吗？
So did you manage to do that?
或者至少尝试一下？
Or at least try it?
好吧，我当然希望如此。
Well, I sure hope so.
但无论如何，当然，
But anyway, of course,
我们再次使用 a 元素。
we use the a element again.
然后我们指定href
Then we specify href
好吧，回过头来，我们只说 index.html。
and well, to go back, we just say index.html.
然后在这里我们可以指定任何文本，
And then here we can specify any text,
我没有告诉你是哪一个
which I didn't tell you which one
因为这并不重要。
because it doesn't really matter.
就说回家吧
Let's just say back to home
或类似的东西。
or something like that.
给它一个保存。
Give it a save.
现在，一旦我们重新加载它，
And now once we reload it,
我们有我们的链接，我们可以点击它
we have our link, we can click it
所以现在我们基本上可以回去了
and so now we can basically go back
在这两页之间来回
and forth between these two pages
因为它们现在通过这些链接连接起来。
because they're now connected through these links.
所以我们可以去博客，
So we can go to the blog,
我们可以来回移动等等。
we can go back and forth and so on and so forth.
好吧，让我们在这里关闭这个。
All right, so let's close up this one here.
我们不再需要它了。
We don't need it anymore.
刚刚结束，
And just to finish,
我们实际上也可以指定一个链接
we can also actually specify a link
那不会去任何地方。
that doesn't go anywhere.
所以让我也向你展示一下。
So let me show that to you as well.
所以我们先写内容
So let's just write the content first
在这里我有我认为的挑战
and here I have Challenges I think
在演示中。
in the demo.
所以我们有挑战 Flexbox 和 CSS Grid。
So we have Challenges Flexbox and CSS Grid.
所以这就是挑战
So that's Challenges
但是看看现在会发生什么
but watch what happens now
当我像这样重新加载页面时。
when I reload the page like this.
所以你看到它只说挑战
So you see that it only says challenge
但请注意它只是普通文本。
but notice how it's just normal text.
它不是蓝色也不是下划线，
It's not blue and not underlined,
所以它显然不是一个链接，对吧？
so it's clearly not a link, right?
所以即使它实际上是一个锚元素
So even though it is actually an anchor element
但是是什么让锚元素真正成为链接
but what makes an anchor element really a link
是 href 属性。
is the href property.
所以我们真的需要指定它，
And so we really need to specify it,
否则它根本不是一个链接。
otherwise it is not a link at all.
那么它只是一个锚，
It is then just an anchor,
这不是很有用。
which is not really useful.
但是如果我们不希望它指向任何地方怎么办
But what if we don't want this to point anywhere
正如我所说？
as I was saying?
嗯，解决方案
Well, the solution to that
是在此处指定此井号。
is to specify this hash symbol right here.
对？
Right?
所以如果我现在保存并重新加载，
So if I now save it and reload,
然后我们回到这实际上是一个链接。
then we are back to this being a link actually.
它只是没有指向任何地方。
It just doesn't point anywhere.
单击此链接时会发生什么
What happens when you click on this link
是基本上它回到顶部
is that basically it goes back to the top
当前页面，好吗？
of this current page, okay?
在课程的稍后部分，
And a little bit later in the course,
我们实际上会利用
we will actually make use
这种行为，但现在，
of this behavior but for now,
我只是想让你知道
I just want you to know
这就是我们可以指定链接的方式
that this is how we can specify links
当我们还没有他们的 URL 时
when we don't have any URL yet for them
或者没有任何页面。
or don't have any page.
所以基本上，这就像一个占位符链接。
So basically, this is like a placeholder link.
好的？
Okay?
所以让我们在这里复制两次。
And so let's just copy this here twice.
没必要再写了。
There's no need to write it again.
但当然，如果你愿意，
But of course, if you want,
你可以写再次。
you can write it again.
所以只针对这个 Flexbox 和 CSS Grid。
So just for this Flexbox and CSS Grid.
所以只是为了让导航看起来
So just to make that navigation look
有点像完整的。
a bit more like complete.
但所有这些链接，
But all of these link,
他们不应该指向任何地方。
they should not point anywhere.
好的，这就是您指定链接的方式
Okay, and this is how you specify links
或超链接或锚点，我们也可以在 HTML 中调用它们。
or hyperlinks or anchors as we can also call them in HTML.
所以这是一个非常重要的部分
So this is a really important part
正如我一开始所说的那样
of the web as I said in the very beginning
因此，请确保您了解它们的工作原理
and so make sure that you understand how they work
以及我们如何将它们放在我们自己的网页中。
and how we place them inside our own webpages.